RAE MALSCH

Milwaukee. WI

CONTACT

- malschrae@gmail.com
- **J** 262.880.3258
- krmalsch.com *

TOOLKIT



OTHER SKILLS

Art Direction
Concepting
Photo Retouch
Email Campaign/Design
Responsive Web Design
Wireframing
Prototyping
User Research/Stories
Agile

ABOUT ME

I am a self-starter with strong interpersonal skills. Building positive relationships with team members is essential in successful team collaboration. I am passionate about understanding the user journey, and making their experience simple while beautifully designed (no matter the underlying complexity). I also have a great sense of humor.

Output

Description:

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer | Wantable | Milwaukee | 4.2018 - current
Responsible for shaping the internal and customer-facing
products and innovating/optimizing existing experiences and
processes. I use an Agile process of documenting user research/
journeys/flows, wire-framing, visual mock-ups, lo-fi and hifi prototypes, utilizing feedback along the way. I work closely
with developers to ensure the designs implemented correctly.
Please do not judge based on the design of wantable.com. It is
undergoing a major re-design.

Web Designer | UW-Milwaukee | 8.2016 - 4.2018 Responsible for UX vision and strategy of UWM.edu. After collaborating with stakeholders to define the project scope, I sketched, made wire-frames, visual mock-ups, Io-fi prototypes and developed final production web pages and micro-sites; taking the project from concept to completion.

Digital Designer | Kohls | 8.2015 - 8.2016 | Contractor/Freelance Implemented digital projects (such as emails, landing pages, loyalty and social campaigns) from conception to completion. Collaborated with stakeholders and creative team on all projects to develop creative solutions for great user experience.

Digital Designer | Bon-Ton | 1.2011 - 8.2015 Designed digital projects across multiple channels (website, emails, banner ads, blog, social media).

EDUCATION

UW-Parkside | 1 yr. Digital Design (5.2009 B.A.)

UMN - Twin Cities | 2 yrs. Fine Arts + Digital Design

University of Sydney, AU | 1 yr. Digital Design + Indigenous Studies

^{*} Please note that my portfolio does not contain UX work from my current position. My customer-facing + internal product designs are still in the QA process. Happy to provide samples upon request.